CAKES

AND HOW TO MAKE THEM


BRIDES CAKE LOAF

 ½ cup butter,
 2 cups sugar,
 1 cup milk,
 1 cup corn starch,
 2 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 1 teaspoonful vanilla,
 Whites of 8 eggs,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder.

Sift all dry ingredients before measuring. Cream the butter and sugar
well, then add the whites of 2 eggs, unbeaten, and cream or beat well.
Add the flavoring, then add a little of the milk, sift in a little
of Gold Medal Flour which has been measured and sifted with baking
powder and corn starch. Beat, then add a little more milk and flour
and so on until all is used. Lastly, fold in lightly the whites of the
remaining 6 eggs which have been beaten light and dry. Bake one hour in
a moderate oven, and when cold, ice with marshmallow icing.


BROWN STONE CAKE

One and one-half cupfuls sugar cream with one-half cupful butter, add
one-half cupful sweet milk; three tablespoonfuls chocolate (rounding)
dissolved in one-half cupful of warm water, four well beaten eggs, one
teaspoonful baking powder, two cupfuls flour; flavor with vanilla, bake
in long pan.—Mrs. Cora Dixon.


FROSTING

Two small teacupfuls of powdered sugar creamed with butter size of an
egg, thin with cream, add the beaten white of one egg and one cup of
walnuts chopped fine.—Mrs. Cora Dixon.


WEDDING CAKE

 1 pound butter,
 1 pound sugar,
 12 eggs,
 1 pound Gold Medal Flour,
 2 teaspoonfuls each of cinnamon and mace,
 1 teaspoonful each of nutmeg and allspice,
 ½ teaspoonful cloves,
 2 pounds raisins,
 2 pounds currants,
 1 pound citron,
 1 pound almonds,
 1 wineglass brandy,
 1 lemon.

Line the pans with three thicknesses of paper; butter the top layer.
Seed and chop the raisins, wash and dry the currants, cut the citron in
uniform slices, about one-eighth of an inch thick, blanch the almonds
and chop fine. Mix all the fruit but the citron with the dough, insert
pieces of citron after dough is poured into pan.


POUND CAKE

 1 pound butter,
 1 pound sugar,
 10 eggs,
 1 pound Gold Medal Flour,
 ½ wine glass wine,
 ½ wine glass brandy.

Cream the butter; add the sugar, yolks of the eggs, wine, brandy,
whites of the eggs, and the flour. Place currants into one-quarter
of the dough, and almonds, blanched and pounded in rose water, into
another part; leave the remainder plain. Fill very small round tins
three-quarter full. Into half of those containing the plain dough put
small pieces of citron, three in each, inserting the citron upright a
little way into the dough. Sift sugar over the tops of those containing
the citron and almond before putting them into the oven. Bake 20
minutes. Frost the plain and currant cakes. Pound cake is lighter when
baked in small cakes than in loaves.


WHIPPED CREAM CAKE

 2 cups sugar,
 ½ cup butter,
 2 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 Yolks 8 eggs,
 1 teaspoonful lemon extract,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 1 cup corn starch.

Sift all dry materials before measuring. Cream sugar and butter well,
add gradually the yolks that have been beaten, beating all until very
light and creamy, then add the flavoring. Then alternate milk and Gold
Medal Flour that has been mixed with the corn starch and baking powder.
Bake in well-buttered layer pans, when cold put between the layers,
rich dry whipped cream, sweetened, using powdered sugar and flavoring.
Add ½ cup more sugar to remaining cream and use as icing, allowing 2
hours to harden.


LADY BALTIMORE CAKE

 1 cup butter,
 2 cups granulated sugar,
 1 cup milk,
 3½ cups Gold Medal Flour,
 3 level teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 1 teaspoonful rosewater,
 Whites of 6 eggs beaten dry.

Cream the butter and beat in the sugar gradually. Sift together the
flour and baking powder and add to the butter and sugar alternately
with the milk and rose water. Lastly, add the egg whites. Bake in three
layer cake pans. Put the layers together with the following frosting:


FROSTING FOR LADY BALTIMORE CAKE

 3 cups granulated sugar,
 1 cup boiling water,
 Whites of 3 eggs,
 1 cup chopped raisins,
 1 cup chopped nutmeats,
 5 figs cut in thin slices.

Stir the sugar and water until the sugar is dissolved, then let boil
without stirring until the syrup from a spoon will spin a long thread,
pour upon the whites of the eggs, beaten dry, beating constantly
meanwhile. Continue the beating until the frosting is cold. Add the
fruit and spread upon the cake.


DEVIL CAKE

 ½ cup butter,
 1 cup sugar,
 Yolks of 3 eggs,
 ¾ cup powdered sugar,
 ½ cup milk,
 1 teaspoonful vanilla,
 ½ teaspoonful cinnamon,
 ¼ teaspoonful cloves,
 2 level teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 3 ounces, chocolate, melted,
 1¾ cups sifted Gold Medal Flour,
 Whites of 3 eggs beaten dry.

Cream the butter and add the cup of sugar. Beat the yolks, add the
¾ cup of sugar and beat the two sugar mixtures together. Add the
chocolate, then the flour, sifted three times with the baking powder
and spices, then the milk, extract and whites of eggs. Bake in two
layers and put together with a fruit icing. Spread white icing above.


FROSTING FOR DEVIL CAKE

 1½ cups sugar,
 ¾ cup water,
 Whites of 2 eggs, beaten dry,
 ¼ cup each Sultana raisins, glace cherries and pecan nut meats.

Boil the sugar and water until the syrup spins a thread, and gradually
beat it into the whites of eggs. When cold put a few spoonfuls over the
fruit and nuts and put between the layers. Spread the rest on top of
the cake.


TO MIX CAKES CONTAINING NO BUTTER

Beat the egg yolks until very light and thick. Add the sugar gradually,
beating till very light and spongy. Add the flavoring and liquid,
if used. Have the whites of eggs whipped to a stiff froth. Add them
alternately with the sifted Gold Medal Flour (mixed with baking
powder), and cut both in very lightly and quickly.


TO MIX CAKES CONTAINING BUTTER

Cream the butter, beating till light. Gradually add the sugar, beating
till light and creamy. Add the yolks of eggs beaten till light, then
the flavoring. Beat in alternately the liquid and Gold Medal Flour,
the latter mixed with salt and baking powder. Lastly, add the beaten
whites, and fruit, if used.


CREAM PUFFS

 ½ pint milk,
 5 ounces sifted Gold Medal Flour,
 5 eggs,
 ¼ pound butter.

Put the milk and butter in a sauce pan on the fire. When butter is all
melted and boiling stir in the flour. When partly cool add 5 eggs, one
at a time. Put the mixture in a bag with large tube and lay out into
about the size of large sponge drops, on a buttered pan; brush with
egg. Bake in hot oven. When done cut open on one side and fill with
whipped cream, sweetened. Flavor to suit.


CREAM PUFF FILLING

 1 quart milk,
 ¾ pound sugar,
 6 ounces Gold Medal Flour,
 ½ pint of yolks,
 Flavor to taste.

Put the milk on the stove; when it comes to a boil put in the sugar,
flour and eggs, after beating them together thoroughly. Be careful not
to let it burn.



SPONGE CAKE

Four eggs beaten separately; then beat together 2 cups sugar slowly
beaten in, 2 cups Gold Medal Flour, 1 teaspoonful baking powder, a
pinch of salt; last of all 1 cup boiling water, 1 teaspoonful lemon.
Heat the pan.


MAMMY BELDON CAKE

One cup sugar, ¾ cup butter, 4 eggs, 1½ cups milk. Cream butter and
sugar together, beat and add yolks of eggs, then milk, 3 cups Gold
Medal Flour, thoroughly mixed with 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder, 1
teaspoonful vanilla, beat 20 minutes, beat whites of eggs to a stiff
froth and add stirring in gently. Bake in layers or 40 minutes as a
whole.


FILLING FOR ABOVE

Take about 24 marshmallows, chopped fine, 1 teacupful sugar, boiled
until thread; stirring briskly, into marshmallows until cool, flavor to
taste, spread between layers. Sprinkle with assorted colored sugar for
rainbow effect.—Mrs. E. F. Kiessling, Reno, Nev.



SPICE CAKE

Three eggs, one cup of sugar, one cup of syrup, one cup butter, one cup
sweet milk, two teaspoonfuls baking powder, one teaspoonful spices,
flour; do not stir too thick.—Mrs. Cora Dixon.


WHIPPED CREAM CAKE

 2 cups sugar,
 ½ cup butter,
 2 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 Yolks 8 eggs,
 1 teaspoon lemon extract,
 2 teaspoons baking powder,
 1 cup corn starch.

Sift all dry materials before measuring. Cream sugar and butter well,
add gradually the yolks that have been beaten, beating all until very
light and creamy, then add the flavoring. Then alternate milk and Gold
Medal Flour that has been mixed with the corn starch and baking powder.
Bake in well buttered layer pans, when cold put between the layers,
rich dry whipped cream, sweetened, using powdered sugar and flavoring.
Add ½ cup more sugar to remaining cream and use as icing, allowing 2
hours to harden.


LAYER CAKE (Plain)

 1 cup sugar,
 ¼ cup butter,
 2 good cups Gold Medal Flour,
 1 cup sweet milk,
 1 teaspoonful vanilla,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder.

Melt the butter, add sugar, beat till creamy, add one egg at a time,
beating well, then pour in milk, and sifted baking powder and flour.
Add vanilla and stir quickly. Bake in four well-greased layer tins.
Usually requires ten minutes to bake. Use any good filling.


FUDGE CAKE

 ½ cup butter,
 1 cup sugar,
 1 cup milk,
 ¼ cup chocolate,
 ¼ cup walnuts,
 2 eggs,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 2 heaping cups Gold Medal Flour.

Melt butter in pan over steam, cream the sugar and butter together,
add eggs, beating well, add milk. Sift in flour, baking powder and
ground chocolate, put in broken nuts, stir batter quickly. Bake in
well-greased cake tins.


POUND LOAF CAKE

 1 cup butter,
 1 cup milk,
 1½ cups sugar,
 2 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 5 eggs,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 2 teaspoonfuls vanilla.

Melt butter, add sugar, cream butter and sugar together, then add yolks
of eggs one at a time, beating well, then milk, sift in the flour and
baking powder, and beat the whites of the eggs to a stiff froth before
adding. Bake in a deep, well-greased pan. Bake in a slow oven for from
thirty to forty minutes. Stir in the vanilla with the milk.


MARGUERITES

Mix ¼ cup hickorynuts with the beaten whites of 2 eggs and 1
tablespoonful sugar. Heap this mixture up on Saratoga crackers and set
in oven to brown slightly.



NUT CAKE

 ½ pound hickory nut meats,
 Scant cup of sugar,
 1 teaspoonful cinnamon,
 1 teaspoonful vanilla,
 Whites of 3 or 4 eggs, according to size.

Roll the nut meats fine, beat the eggs stiff and add sugar to them. Mix
all ingredients together. The consistency must be stiff. Drop from a
teaspoon on buttered pan. Bake in moderate oven. If hickory nuts are
not procurable, English walnuts and pecans may be substituted.


SPONGE CAKE

 3 eggs,
 1 scant cup sugar,
 1 tablespoonful hot water,
 2 teaspoonfuls vinegar,
 ½ teaspoonful salt,
 ½ teaspoonful extract of lemon,
 1 cup Gold Medal Flour,
 ½ teaspoonful baking powder.

Beat the yolks until thick and light; add sugar gradually and continue
beating; then add water and vinegar; add the salt to the whites
and beat until very stiff; sift the flour with baking powder three
times; add the flavoring and fold in the flour and the beaten whites
alternately as gently as possible. Bake about 30 minutes in slow oven
until well risen; then increase the heat. Invert to cool, then remove
from pan.


WALNUT TORTE

 1 pound English walnuts or almonds,
 1 cup sugar,
 9 eggs,
 ¼ cup grated chocolate,
 ½ cup of fine cracker crumbs.

Chop the nuts, reserving twenty-three halves for decorating the top.
Mix the chopped nuts and chocolate. Beat yolks thoroughly with Dover
beater, add sugar and beat again. Then mix with the nuts, crumbs and
chocolate, and stir well. Beat whites of eggs until stiff and add
lastly, just as in sponge cake. Bake in moderate oven forty-five
minutes in prepared spring form.


UNEEDA BISCUIT TORTE

Yolks of 8 eggs with 1¾ cups sugar—beat well. Ten Uneeda Biscuits
rolled fine. One cup grated walnuts.

Grated rind and juice of one-half lemon—biscuits added to eggs—then
nuts and lemon—lastly beaten whites of 8 eggs. Bake in slow oven 40
minutes. Do not grease pan.


CREAM FOR CREAM CAKES

 1 quart milk,
 4 eggs,
 ½ pound powdered sugar,
 3 ounces corn starch,
 Whites of six eggs,
 A little salt,
 Vanilla flavor to taste.

Put the milk on the fire in a pan to boil; while the milk is coming
to a boil put the eggs, sugar, corn starch and salt into a dish and
mix well together; when the milk boils turn this into it, stirring the
while, and as soon as it all comes to a boil take it off, and when
nearly cold add the whites of the six eggs, beat up to a stiff froth.


JAM CAKE

Two cups sugar, 2 cups jam, 3 cups Gold Medal Flour, 1 teaspoonful
cinnamon, 5 eggs, 1 teaspoonful baking powder, 1 cup butter, 1 cup sour
milk, 1 nutmeg, 1 teaspoonful vanilla, 1 teaspoonful soda.



LADY FINGERS

 1 pound sugar,
 1 dozen eggs,
 1 pound Gold Medal Flour,
 Juice and rind of one lemon.

Mix sugar and eggs with an egg-beater to a light foam, until it is
filled with little bubbles; add the juice and grated rind of lemon,
mix flour in carefully, so as not to toughen mixture; lay on paper the
shape of the little finger and sprinkle with powdered sugar, and bake
in large sheet pans; when done take from the pans and let cool. Wet the
under side of the paper and they will come off easily, and then put two
of the flat sides together.


ORANGE CAKE

 5 eggs,
 ½ pound pulverized sugar,
 1 orange,
 ½ pound Gold Medal Flour,
 1½ dessert spoonfuls rose water.

Separate the whites from the yolks of eggs, then beat the whites and
rose water together with a clean whisk for half an hour; then add the
sugar and grated rind of the orange; when well mixed add juice of the
orange and the yolks of eggs; beat until smooth, then add flour, after
putting it through a fine sieve; mix up lightly and put in a deep pan
and bake about one hour in a cool oven. Lemon cake may be made the same
way by substituting lemons for the oranges.



BOSTON LEMON SNAPS

 1 pound Gold Medal Flour,
 ¼ pound butter,
 12 ounces sugar,
 3 eggs,
 ½ ounce cream of tartar,
 Lemon flavor.

Rub the butter and flour together then add the sugar, eggs, cream of
tartar and flavor; mix all together, break up in small pieces and make
in little balls; put on pans and flatten out with the hand; bake in a
cool oven.


GRAND DUKE CAKE

Cream together ⅔ cup butter and 2 cups sugar. Add 1 cup milk
alternately with 3½ cups Gold Medal Flour sifted with 2 teaspoonfuls
baking powder, ¼ teaspoonful almond, ¾ teaspoonful vanilla, and beat
well. Fold in stiffly beaten whites of 6 eggs. Bake in three square
layer-cake tins. Put layers together with raisin frosting. Boil 3
cups sugar with 1 cup water until syrup will spin thread. Pour onto
whites of 3 eggs beaten very stiff. Beat until cool, and add 1¼ cups
seeded raisins cut fine, ¾ cup chopped nuts and ½ cup chopped candied
apricots, plums, pineapple or cherries.



SOUR MILK DOUGHNUTS

 2 eggs, beaten light,
 3 even tablespoonfuls melted butter,
 4 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 1 cup sugar,
 1 cup sour milk,
 ½ teaspoonful soda,
 1 saltspoonful each of cinnamon and salt.

Enough more Gold Medal Flour to make just soft enough to roll out.
Mix the dough rather soft at first. Have the board well floured, and
the fat heating. Roll only a large spoonful at first. Cut into rings
with an open cutter. Mix the trimmings with another spoonful. Work it
lightly till well floured and roll again. Roll and cut all out before
frying. The fat should be hot enough for the dough to rise to the top
instantly.


DOUGHNUTS AND CRULLERS

The fat should be in a deep pot (to obviate any danger of boiling
over), and should be of sufficient depth to cover the dough, when
first dropped in. It should be smoking hot, or the dough will absorb
grease and be soggy. Not more than half a dozen should be dropped in at
any one time, or the fat will be unduly cooled and some of the cakes
submerged during the entire cooking; in which case the cakes when
cooked will be greasy and not light. One or two pieces of dough should
be cooked first as testers. When done the cakes should be drained on
unglazed paper, then rolled in powdered sugar.


ALMOND COOKIES

 ½ cup butter,
 ⅓ cup almonds blanched and finely chopped,
 ¼ teaspoonful cloves,
 ⅛ teaspoonful salt,
 2 tablespoonfuls sherry wine,
 1 cup Gold Medal Rolled Oats,
 1 cup sugar,
 1 egg beaten lightly,
 ½ teaspoonful cinnamon,
 ½ teaspoonful nutmeg,
 Grated rind of half a lemon,
 1 cup Gold Medal Flour,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder.

Cream the butter; add the sugar gradually; add egg well beaten without
separating; almonds, Gold Medal Flour, oats, spices, baking powder,
thoroughly mixed; add lemon rind and sherry. Drop in piles about the
size of an English walnut—1½ inches apart on a buttered sheet. Spread
with a spatula and press the half of an almond meat on top of each.
Bake in a moderate oven 12 to 15 minutes.


GERMAN DOUGHNUTS

Scald 1 pint milk, pour hot over 1 pint Gold Medal Flour, and beat
till smooth; add ½ teaspoonful salt, and let cool. Add beaten yolks of
4 eggs, 1 tablespoonful melted butter, 1 teaspoonful flavoring, ½ cup
sugar, beaten whites of eggs, 1 cup flour mixed with 2 teaspoonfuls
baking powder, and more flour to make a soft dough. Roll, cut, and fry.


DOUGHNUTS

 2 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 3 teaspoonfuls baking powder,
 1 egg,
 4 tablespoonfuls sugar,
 1 teaspoonful nutmeg,
 1 cup milk.

Sift the dry ingredients together, beat the egg until light and add
to the milk, and if flavor is used, add it now. Pour the liquid into
the flour and mix thoroughly and roll one-half inch thick, cut with a
doughnut cutter and drop into smoking hot fat.



BATH BUNS

Mix and sift 1 quart Gold Medal Flour, 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder,
½ teaspoonful salt, ⅔ cup sugar, 1 teaspoonful powdered cinnamon. Add
grated rind 1 lemon, ½ cup chopped citron. Rub in ½ cup butter. Beat 6
egg yolks, add ⅔ cup milk, and mix all to soft dough, adding more milk
if needed. Mold with the hands in round buns. Place 1 inch apart on
greased pans. Brush with milk, sprinkle with chopped citron, and bake
in quick oven.


ROLLED OATS CRISPS

 2 eggs,
 2½ cups Gold Medal Rolled Oats,
 ½ teaspoonful salt,
 ¾ cup brown sugar,
 1 teaspoonful baking powder,
 1 tablespoonful shortening,
 ½ teaspoonful vanilla.

Beat up eggs thoroughly; add sugar gradually and continue with the
beating; put in salt and extract; mix separately the shortening with
the rolled oats and then mix all together. Drop in small pieces on
greased baking pan, leaving a good space between. Bake in a hot quick
oven until crisp and brown. Take off with a knife.


HUCKLEBERRY SHORT CAKE

Two cups sugar, ½ cup butter, 1 teaspoonful salt, 1 pint milk, 2
heaping teaspoonfuls baking powder sifted into 3 cups Gold Medal Flour,
1 quart washed and well-drained huckleberries, more flour to make a
very thick batter. Bake in greased dripping-pan, break in squares,
serve hot with butter.


STRAWBERRY OR RASPBERRY SHORT CAKE

Pick, hull, wash, and drain berries. Sweeten, spread between layers
of short cake. Garnish top layer with large whole berries, dust with
sugar, and serve with cream or custard.


CURRANT LOAF

 3 cups Gold Medal Flour,
 ⅔ cup butter,
 ½ cup sugar,
 ½ teaspoonful salt,
 1 cup cleaned currants,
 Grated rind 1 lemon,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder.

Mix dry ingredients, rub in butter, add currants and lemon rind, mix
to a very thick drop batter with cold milk. Turn into well-greased
loaf-pan, bake 1 hour in moderate oven.


MOLASSES COOKIES

 1 quart molasses,
 2 ounces soda,
 1 pint and one gill of water,
 ¼ pound lard,
 Sufficient Gold Medal Flour to mix.

Put the molasses, water, soda and lard in a bowl, mix them together;
then add flour enough to make a nice dough, suitable to roll out and
cut; wash with milk or water on top.

Molasses cookies are very common cakes, but they are not easy to
make, for the reason that there is no rule you can work by that will
answer in all cases. All molasses does not work alike; some kinds will
bear more water than others, and the weather has to be taken into
consideration. In cold weather you can use more water than in warm
weather. Sometimes you can use the same quantity of water as molasses.
Be very careful and not get the dough too stiff, and do not work any
more than is necessary to mix.


SPICE CAKES

Two cups sugar, ½ cup butter, cup sour milk, 2 cups Gold Medal Flour, a
good ½ teaspoonful soda, the yolks of 5 eggs, 3 teaspoonfuls cinnamon,
2 teaspoonfuls cloves, 2 teaspoonfuls allspice, 1 nutmeg.



OATMEAL COOKIES

Two and one-quarter cups Gold Medal Flour, 1 cup sugar, 2 eggs, 1
teaspoonful soda, 2½ cups oatmeal, 1 cup butter, 2 tablespoonfuls sour
milk, flavor to taste. Roll, cut and bake quickly.


COCOANUT DROP COOKIES

One cup brown sugar, 1 cup butter, ½ cup sour milk or ¼ cup butter and
½ cup cream, sour, 1 teaspoonful soda in milk, 1 teaspoonful baking
powder, 2 cups Gold Medal Flour, 1 box cocoanut. Drop from spoon on
greased pans.


GINGER SNAPS

One cup sugar, 1 cup Orleans molasses, 1 cup butter, heat them boiling
hot, take from the stove and stir in 1 cup Gold Medal Flour while hot,
let cool, add 2 teaspoonfuls soda, dissolve in a little vinegar, 2
eggs, 1 heaping teaspoonful of ginger in the flour, beat all the rest.
Knead enough Gold Medal Flour in to roll out nicely.


EGGLESS CAKE (Fine)

Two cups sugar, 1 cup buttermilk, 4 cups Gold Medal Flour, 1
teaspoonful each nutmeg, cloves, cinnamon and allspice, 2 cups raisins,
chopped fine, 1 cup butter, 1 cup cold coffee, 2 level teaspoonfuls
soda, 1 cup nuts, chopped fine. Mix all together. Add nuts and raisins
last.


PLAIN COOKIES

 ¾ cup butter,
 3 eggs,
 2½ cups Gold Medal Flour,
 1½ cups sugar,
 2 tablespoonfuls milk,
 2 teaspoonfuls baking powder.

Roll thin.

Stir butter and sugar to cream, add beaten eggs, flour, sifted with the
baking powder, and milk. Roll out thin and cut in circles.


GRAHAM WAFERS

 ½ cup butter or nut butter,
 1 cup sugar,
 1 egg,
 1 teaspoonful bicarbonate soda,
 2 tablespoonfuls milk,
 Graham Flour.

Beat the butter to a cream; add the egg and beat again until light.
Gradually beat in the sugar. Dissolve the soda in two tablespoonfuls
of water and add it to the sugar mixture. Add the milk and work in
sufficient graham flour—about three cupfuls to make a very stiff dough.
Knead until the mixture will hold together. Roll into a very thin sheet
and cut into two-inch squares. Lift carefully with a cake-turner, put
into slightly greased pans and bake in a moderate oven until thoroughly
crisp and lightly browned—about eight minutes.


PEANUT SNAPS

 1½ cups butter,
 2 cups sugar,
 6 eggs,
 1½ pints Gold Medal Flour,
 ½ cup cornstarch,
 1 teaspoonful baking powder,
 1 teaspoonful extract lemon,
 ½ cup chopped peanuts mixed with
 ½ cup granulated sugar.

Rub the butter and sugar smooth; add the beaten eggs, the Gold Medal
Flour, cornstarch, and powder, sifted together, and the extract; flour
the board, roll out the dough rather thin, cut out with biscuit-cutter,
roll in the chopped peanuts and sugar, lay on greased baking-tin; bake
in rather hot oven 8 to 10 minutes.



Fillings, Frostings and Icings


BOILED CHOCOLATE FROSTING

 2 ounces chocolate,
 ½ cup cream,
 2 whites of eggs,
 Vanilla,
 Powdered sugar.

Boil chocolate and cream and when cool add vanilla. Beat the whites to
a stiff froth, add powdered sugar until stiff enough to cut. Combine
the two mixtures, beat and spread.


CARAMEL FROSTING

 ¾ pound maple sugar, scraped,
 ¾ pound brown sugar,
 Butter, size of an egg,
 1½ cups cream.

Mix and boil slowly for forty minutes. Remove from stove and stir over
ice until the proper consistency to spread. If too stiff, thin with
cream. Dip knife in cream to spread.


NUT OR FRUIT FILLING

 ½ cup fruit (chopped fine),
 Boiled frosting,
 ½ cup nuts (chopped fine).

To boiled icing add one cup chopped walnuts, almonds, pecans, hickory,
hazel nuts, chopped figs, dates, raisins, or selected prunes,
separately or in combination.


MARSHMALLOW FROSTING

 ½ pound marshmallows,
 ¼ cup milk or water,
 Whites of 2 eggs,
 1 teaspoonful vanilla.

Break the marshmallows in pieces, add milk or water, and put in double
boiler, over boiling water. Stir until melted. Take from fire and while
hot pour into the well beaten whites of eggs. Add vanilla.


BOILED ICING

 1 cup sugar,
 ⅓ cup water,
 ¼ teaspoonful cream of tartar,
 1 teaspoonful flavoring,
 1 egg white (large).

Beat white of egg until frothy, add the cream of tartar and beat until
stiff and dry. Make syrup of sugar and water. When it has reached the
honey stage, or drops heavily from spoon, add 5 tablespoonfuls slowly
to egg, beating in well. Then cook the remainder of the syrup until it
threads and pour over the egg, beating thoroughly. Add flavoring and
beat until cool enough to spread.


WHIPPED CREAM FILLING WITH PINEAPPLE AND NUTS

 1 yolk of egg,
 2 tablespoonfuls powdered sugar,
 ½ cup whipped cream,
 1 cup nut kernels, or ½ cup nuts and ½ cup pineapple.

Whip cream, same as above, using one-half cupful nuts and one-half
cupful pineapple, all chopped up.


WHIPPED CREAM FILLING

 ¾ cup thick cream,
 ¼ cup powdered sugar,
 White of 1 egg,
 ½ teaspoonful vanilla.

Set medium sized bowl in pan of crushed ice to which water has been
added. Place cream in bowl and beat until stiff, with wire whip or, if
possible, use patent cream whipper. Whip up well that air bubbles may
not be too large. Add sugar, white of egg beaten stiff, and vanilla.
Keep cool.


CHOCOLATE FILLING

 ½ cup sugar,
 ½ cup milk,
 ½ cup grated chocolate,
 Yolk of 1 egg,
 ½ teaspoonful vanilla.

Melt chocolate, add sugar and milk, and boil when it forms a soft ball
in cold water, remove from fire. Add beaten yolk and vanilla. Cool and
spread between layers.


ICING FOR WHITE CAKE

 1½ cups sugar,
 1 cup water,
 2 eggs (whites).

Boil sugar and water until it threads well, pour over the egg whites
well beaten, beating all the time, when partly cool add ½ cup chopped
pineapple.
